This video is a continuation of the previous video where we'll be finishing up
这个视频是上一个视频的延续，我们将在前面的视频中结束
co-generation for the simple language dealing with function calls, function
共同生成处理函数调用、函数
definitions and variable references. So just to remind you what we're working on,
定义和变量引用。所以为了提醒你们我们在做什么，
here is the simple language And again, we have a bunch of different kinds of
这是简单的语言，再一次，我们有一堆不同类型的
expressions And we dealt with all of these last time except for variable references
表达式，上一次我们讨论了除变量引用之外的所有这些表达式
and function calls And of course, we also have function definitions. So, as I said
和函数调用，当然，我们也有函数定义。所以，就像我说的
in the introduction these are the three constructs we'll be looking at in this
在引言中，这些是我们将在本示例中查看的三个结构
video. >> The main issue in designing the co-generation for function calls and
录像带。>>设计函数调用和函数调用联合生成的主要问题
function definitions is that both of these will depend intimately on the layout of
函数定义是，这两者都将密切依赖于
the activation record. So really, co-generation for function calls,
激活记录。所以真的，函数调用的联合生成，
co-generation for function definitions and the layout of the activation record all
函数定义和激活记录布局的联合生成
need to be designed together. Now for this particular language, a very simple
需要一起设计。现在对于这种特殊的语言，一个非常简单的
activation record will be sufficient. Because we are using a stack machine, we
激活记录就足够了。因为我们使用的是堆叠机，所以我们
are modeling a stack machine in our code generation. The results of a function call
在我们的代码生成中对堆栈机器进行建模。函数调用的结果
will always be in the accumulator and that means there is no need to store the
将始终位于累加器中，这意味着不需要存储
results of the function call in the activation record And furthermore, the
激活记录中函数调用的结果，而且
activation record will hold the actual parameters. So when we go to computer
激活记录将保存实际参数。所以当我们去电脑的时候
function call with arguments X1 through XN, we will push those arguments onto the
带有参数X1到Xn的函数调用，我们将把这些参数推送到
stack And as it happens, these are the only variables in this language that are
堆栈，并且碰巧的是，这是该语言中仅有的变量
no local or global variables other than the arguments to a function call And so
除函数调用的参数外没有局部或全局变量，因此
those are the only variables that will need to be stored in the activation
这些是激活中需要存储的唯一变量
record. Now recall that the stack machine discipline guarantees that the stack
录音。现在回想一下，堆栈机器规则保证堆栈
pointer is preserved across function calls. So the stack pointer will be
指针在函数调用之间保留。因此堆栈指针将为
exactly the same when we exit from a function call, as it was when we entered
当我们从函数调用中退出时，与我们进入函数调用时完全相同
the function call And this means we won't need a control link in our activation
函数调用，这意味着我们在激活时不需要控制链接
record. The point of a control link is to help us find the previous activat ion, and
录音。控制链接的目的是帮助我们找到之前的激活项，并且
since, the stack pointer is preserved, it will have no trouble finding it when we
因为堆栈指针是保留的，所以当我们执行以下操作时，它将毫不费力地找到它
return from our function call, and we'll never need to look at another activation
从我们的函数调用返回，我们再也不需要查看另一个激活
during a function call since there are no non-local variables in the language. We
在函数调用期间，因为语言中没有非局部变量。我们
will however need the return address and that will need to be stored somewhere in
但是，需要返回地址，并且该地址需要存储在
the activation record And, one more thing. It turns out that a pointer to the current
激活记录，还有一件事。事实证明，指向当前
activation will be useful. Now this is to the current activation, not to the
激活会很有用。这是针对当前激活的，而不是针对
previous activation And this pointer will live in the register, FP, which stands for
上一次激活，该指针将位于寄存器fp中，该寄存器表示
Frame Pointer. This is a conventional, this is a, this is the register name on
帧指针。这是一种常规，这是一种，这是寄存器上的名称
the MIPS and the name is chosen, to denote the frame pointer And by
选择MIPS和名称来表示帧指针，并通过
convention, the compilers put the frame pointer there. What the frame pointer is
按照惯例，编译器将帧指针放在那里。帧指针是什么
good for, well it points to the current frame, so that's what the name comes from.
好的，它指向当前帧，这就是这个名字的由来。
But, what it's good for, we'll see in a few minutes. Right so to summarize for
但是，它有什么好处，我们几分钟后再看。对，所以总结一下
this language an activation record that has the caller's frame pointer, The actual
此语言是一个激活记录，它具有调用方的帧指针、实际的
parameters and the return address will be sufficient. So let's consider a call to
参数和返回地址就足够了。那么让我们考虑一个电话，
the function F and has two arguments X and Y. Then at the time the call is performed
函数F和有两个参数X和Y。然后在执行调用时
before we start executing the body of the function this is what the activation
在我们开始执行函数体之前，这是激活
record will look like, So we'll have the old frame pointer. So this is the frame
记录将如下所示，因此我们将使用旧的帧指针。所以这就是框架
pointer that points to the caller's frame. Not to the frame of the function that
指向调用方框架的指针。而不是指向函数的框架，该函数
we're executing And the reason that it does that is that we have to save it
我们在执行，之所以这样做，是因为我们必须保存它
somewhere because the frame pointer register will be overwritten with the
因为帧指针寄存器将被
frame pointer for the current activation so we have to save the old one, so that we
当前激活的帧指针，因此我们必须保存旧的，这样我们
can restart the caller when we return to it, from the current function. And then
当我们从当前函数返回调用方时，可以重新启动调用方。然后
there the arguments of the function and those that are pushed on the stack in
这里有函数的参数和在堆栈中压入的参数
reverse order. So the last argument is pushed on first and the first argument is
颠倒顺序。因此，最后一个参数首先被推入，第一个参数是
at the top of the stack And the reason for doing it this way is it'll make the
堆栈的顶部，这样做的原因是它将使
indexing to find the a rguments a little bit easier. A little bit simpler And then
建立索引，以便更容易地找到目标。稍微简单一点，然后
We have the stack pointer so there's a, there's nothing here. What will go here is
我们有堆栈指针，所以这里没有任何东西。这里要讲的是
the callee, the function that we're calling, will push on the return address.
被调用者，也就是我们正在调用的函数，将推送返回地址。
So this is where the return address will go And these elements, the callers frame
这就是返回地址将要到达的位置，而这些元素，即调用者帧
pointer, the arguments to the function and the return address of the call function
指针、函数的参数和调用函数的返回地址
will make up the activation record of F. A bit of terminology, the calling sequence
将组成F.的激活记录。一些术语，调用顺序
is the sequence of instructions that both the caller and callee to set up a function
是调用方和被调用方设置函数的指令序列
invocation, okay? So that's referred to in compiler lingo as the calling sequence And
召唤，好吗？因此，这在编译器行话中称为调用序列，
we're going to need a new instruction to show the calling sequence for this for,
我们需要一个新的指令来显示的调用序列，
for function calls. And that will be the jump and link instruction. So jump and
用于函数调用。这就是跳转和链接指令。所以跳起来吧
link what it does is it jumps to the label that it's given as an argument And it
链接它所做的是跳转到它作为参数给出的标签，并且它
saves the address of the next instruction after the jump in link, in the register
将跳转链接之后的下一条指令的地址保存在寄存器中
R.A. Which stands for, return address. So, what would happen in the jump in link
R.A.代表回邮地址。那么，在跳转链接中会发生什么呢？
instructions, if I have jump in link to label L And then there's an add
说明，如果我跳转到标签L的链接，然后有一个添加
instruction that comes next. I don't know what it is. It's the address of this
接下来是指令。我不知道这是什么。这是这个的地址
instruction, the one after the jump in the link that will be stored in the ret-, in
指令，将存储在ret-，in中的链接跳转后的指令
the, in the register RA. So this instruction will jump to L. It will store
在登记册RA中。所以这条指令将跳转到L。它将存储
the address of this add instruction in RAb And it will execute whatever code is at L.
该ADD指令在RAB中的地址，它将执行位于L的任何代码。
And then the code that's at L can execute a jump back to the address in here to
然后L处的代码可以跳回这里的地址
execute the return, to the caller. So now we're ready to actually generate code for
执行对调用者的返回。现在，我们已经准备好实际为以下项生成代码
a function call expression. So let's say we have the call, F of E1 To EN Where of
函数调用表达式。假设我们有E1的F到EN的呼叫
course E1 through EN are expressions. And let me change colors here. So these are
课程E1到EN都是表达式。让我在这里换一下颜色。那么这些是
expressions, here, not values. So how are we going to do that? >> Well, the first
这里是表达式，而不是值。那么我们要怎么做呢？>>好的，第一个
thing we're going to do is we're going to start building, the activation record And
我们要做的是开始建立激活记录，
so we save the current frame pointer. This is the frame pointer for the collar. >>
所以我们保存当前帧指针。这是衣领的帧指针。>>
Okay. >> This is pointing to th e collars frame. >> Right >> And we store that at
好吧。>>这是指向衣领框架的。>>对>>我们将其存储在
the stack pointer. We have to bump the stack pointer. And then we generate code
堆栈指针。我们必须撞击堆栈指针。然后我们生成代码
for the last argument, for EN, right? And so that code gets inserted here And then
最后一个论点，嗯，对吗？所以代码会被插入到这里，然后
we push it on the stack. So we store the results of EN which will be in the
我们将其推送到堆栈上。所以我们将en的结果存储在
accumulator A0 on the stack and then we, bump the stack pointer. Alright, and we'll
堆栈上的累加器A0，然后我们，撞击堆栈指针。好的，我们会
do that for all the arguments finishing up with E-1. So, we generate code for E-1 and
对所有以E-1结尾的论点都这样做。因此，我们为E-1生成代码，
we push it onto the stack. So, now all the arguments are on the stack and now we just
我们把它推到堆栈上。所以，现在所有参数都在堆栈上，现在我们只需
do the jump in link. So, we've done as much of the work or much of the calling
跳入链接。所以，我们已经完成了尽可能多的工作或召唤
sequence as we can do on the caller's side. So, this code is executing in the
序列，就像我们在呼叫方那一侧所能做的那样。因此，此代码在
function in the caller. Okay, so this is the caller side of the calling sequence,
函数在调用方中执行。好的，这是呼叫序列的呼叫方，
and it builds up as much of the activation record as it can. In particular it's
它会尽可能多地建立激活记录。尤其是它
evaluating the actual parameters and pushing them on to the stack to form part
评估实际参数并将其推送到堆栈上以形成部件
of the activation record, for the called function, and then we do the jump and
被调用函数的激活记录，然后我们进行跳转并
link. And we jump to the entry point of the function that we're calling. So we're,
链接。我们跳到正在调用的函数的入口点。所以我们是，
this is a call to, to F, and so we jump to F's entry point. So a few more things to
这是对F的调用，所以我们跳到F的入口点。所以还有几件事要做
note, First of all, as we discussed on the previous slide When we execute the jump in
请注意，首先，正如我们在上一张幻灯片中讨论的那样，当我们在
link instruction that is going to save the return address in the register RA And that
将把返回地址保存在寄存器RA中的链接指令
address will be this address here, the one that comes after the, the address of the
地址将是这里的这个地址，在，地址后面的那个地址
next instruction, after the jump in link instruction And you'll notice also that
下一条指令，在跳转到链接指令之后，您还会注意到
the activation record we've built so far is four times N plus four bytes. So this
到目前为止，我们构建的激活记录是4乘以N加上4个字节。所以这件事
is where N here is the number of arguments. Each argument takes up four
这里的N是参数的数量。每个论点占四个
bytes, and then four bytes for the old frame pointer. Now we're ready to talk
字节，然后四个字节用于旧帧指针。现在我们准备好谈谈了
about the callee side of the calling sequence And we're going to need one new
关于调用序列的被呼叫方，我们需要一个新的
instruction for that. The JR instruction stands for jump register. And it just
这方面的说明。JR指令代表跳转寄存器。而且它只是
jumps to the address in its register argument. So now, the callee side is the
跳转到其寄存器参数中的地址。所以现在，被调用方是
code for the function definition, okay? So this is the co de that actually executes
函数定义的代码，好吗？这就是实际执行的code
the body of the function. And how do we generate code for that? Well let's take a
函数的主体。我们如何为此生成代码呢？好的，让我们拿一张
look. Now actually the very first thing that should be here is that this first
看。现在，实际上首先应该在这里的是，这是第一个
instruction of the call side is the entry point. So, we're missing the label
呼叫侧的指令是入口点。所以，我们找不到标签了
here So this would be labeled F entry. Okay So this is the target of the jump in
这里，所以这将被标记为F条目。好的，这就是跳跃的目标
link instruction. And then the very first thing we do is we set up the frame
链接说明。然后我们要做的第一件事就是架设好框架
pointer. So we copy the current value of the stack pointer into the frame pointer.
指针。因此，我们将堆栈指针的当前值复制到帧指针中。
That sets, that points to the end of the frame for the call-ee, for the new
该设置指向被呼叫方的帧的末尾，用于新的
function that's being executed. We also save the return address at the current
正在执行的函数。我们还将寄信人地址保存在当前
position on the stacks. Remember there was one more thing to do one thing one thing
放置在堆栈上。记住还有一件事要做一件事一件事
that was missing. On the caller side on the caller side of the sequences which is
那东西不见了。在序列的呼叫方一侧的呼叫方一侧
the return address. We don't know the return address until after the jumping
寄信人地址。我们直到跳跃之后才知道回信地址
link instructions executes And so the callee is the one that has to save that
执行链接指令，因此被调用方必须保存该链接
value. Okay so after the jumping link the RA register contains the return address
价值。好的，那么在跳转链接之后，RA寄存器包含返回地址
and that we save it into the frame. All right, and then we push the stack pointer.
我们把它保存到相框里。好的，然后我们按下堆栈指针。
'Kay. And now we just generate code for the body of the function. So now the, at
‘好的。现在我们只为函数体生成代码。
this point the activation record is completely set up, and now we can just
这一点激活记录已经完全设置好了，现在我们只需
generate code for the function body. And after the function body executes, of
为函数体生成代码。在函数体执行之后，
course, the stack pointer will be preserved, and, and that means that the
当然，堆栈指针将被保留，这意味着
return address will be at four offset from the stack pointer, so we can load the
返回地址将位于堆栈指针的四个偏移量，因此我们可以加载
return address back into the return address register And then we can pop the
将地址返回到返回地址寄存器，然后我们可以弹出
stack So here we're going to pop off The current frame from the stack And that's
堆栈，所以这里我们将从堆栈中弹出当前帧，这是
going to be song size, z. Which we I haven't shown you what it is yet But,
将会是歌曲的大小，z。我们还没有给你们展示它是什么，但是，
we'll calculate The size of z in just a minute? This is going to be an immediate
我们马上就能计算出z的大小？这将是一个即刻的
value. So it's a constant that we plug in there And then we load the old frame
价值。所以这是一个常数，我们把它插进去，然后加载旧的框架
pointer. Okay So once we've incremented the stacks we popped off the existing
指针。好的，一旦我们增加了堆栈，我们就会弹出现有的
frame, and so now we're pointing at the frame pointer at the first we're, we're,
帧，所以现在我们指向帧指针，在第一个我们，我们是，
we're pointing at the first thing beyond the previous stack frame, and, what was
我们指的是前一个堆栈帧之外的第一件事，
that, well, that was the first thing that we saved in the stack frame for F, and
这是我们在堆栈框架中为F保存的第一件事，
that's the old frame pointer. So now we restore the old frame pointer so that the
那是旧的帧指针。因此，现在我们恢复旧的帧指针，以便
call, the function that called us, we'll have its frame pointer back, and then now
调用，调用我们的函数，我们会找回它的帧指针，然后现在
we're ready to return it resume execution of the calling function. We just do that
我们已经准备好返回它，继续执行调用函数。我们就这么做
by a jump register to the return address, All right? So note here that the frame
通过跳转寄存器转到返回地址，好吗？请注意，这里的框架
pointer points to the top of the frame, not the bottom of the frame. Okay? So that
指针指向框架的顶部，而不是框架的底部。好吧?所以
will actually be important when we talk about how we use the frame pointer When we
在我们讨论如何使用帧指针时，
get to talking about the variable references next And the callee pops the
接下来开始讨论变量引用，被调用者弹出
return address, The actual arguments in the saved value of the frame pointer from
返回地址，帧指针的保存值中的实际参数来自
the stacks. So the callee pops off the entire activation record, and also
堆栈。因此被呼叫者弹出整个激活记录，并且
restores the caller's frame pointer And what's the value of Z? Well, there are N
恢复调用者的帧指针以及Z的值是多少？嗯，有N个
arguments. Each of which take up four bytes So there's at, so the size of the
争论。每个都占用4个字节，所以在，所以
activation record is four times N. Plus, there are two other values. In the
激活记录是N的四倍，另外还有两个值。在
activation record One is the return address. And the other one is the old
激活记录一是返回地址。另一个是老的
frame pointer. Okay and the space for two more words is eight bytes. So that's the
帧指针。好的，另外两个字的空间是八个字节。所以这就是
size of the activation record. So that's how much we have to add to the stack
激活记录的大小。这就是我们要添加到堆栈中的数量
pointer to pop the activation record for F off the stack. Just to give you a sketch
将F的激活记录从堆栈中弹出的指针。只是想给你一张素描
of, what this looks like before the call. We have the frame pointer for the caller,
在电话之前这是什么样子。我们有调用者的帧指针，
and we have the, The current value of the stack pointer And on entry to the
我们有堆栈指针的当前值，并且在进入
function. Okay, after the calling after the calling functions side of the calling
功能。好的，在调用之后，调用函数端的调用
sequence has completed what's on the stack, well, we have the old frame
序列已经完成了堆栈上的内容，那么，我们有了旧的帧
pointer, and the two arguments, and then the stack pointer points to the next
指针和两个参数，然后堆栈指针指向下一个
unused, location. Which is where the return address will go Alright, then we do
未使用的位置。那就是寄信人地址的位置好的，然后我们就
the jump and link. We jump over, and the return address gets pushed on to the
跳跃和链接。我们跳过，然后把寄信人的地址推到
stack, a nd the frame pointer gets moved to point two, the current value of the
堆栈，然后将帧指针移到指针2，即
frame. Okay, you've got to point to the top of the frame. Okay? And then after the
画框。好的，你要指向画面的顶部。好吧?然后在
call, what has happened? Well, we've popped everything off the stack, we've
打电话，发生什么事了？嗯，我们已经把所有东西都从堆栈里拿出来了，我们已经
popped the entire. Your activation record for the call function off of the stack And
把整个都炸飞了。您的调用函数在堆栈之外的激活记录和
so now notice that we're back in the same state. So again, function calls have to
现在请注意，我们又回到了相同的状态。所以再一次，函数调用必须
preserve the invariant that. The stack is preserved across the call so the stack
保持不变量。堆栈在调用期间保留，因此堆栈
should be exactly the same after the call, as it was on entry to the call. So we are
在调用之后应该与进入调用时完全相同。所以我们是
almost done with code generation for simple language. The last construct we
基本完成了简单语言的代码生成。我们的最后一个结构是
need to talk about is how we generate code for variable references. Now the variables
需要讨论的是我们如何为变量引用生成代码。现在这些变量
of a function again are just its arguments just the parameters to the function. There
函数的参数，也就是它的参数，也就是函数的参数。那里
are no other kinds of variables in this simple language And these variables are
在这个简单的语言中没有其他类型的变量，这些变量是
all in the activation record. So we really all we have to do is generate code to look
都在激活记录里。所以我们真正要做的就是生成代码来查看
up a variable in its appropriate place in the activation record But there is one
在激活记录中的适当位置上移一个变量，但有一个变量
problem, and that's that the stack does grow and shrink with intermediate values.
问题，那就是堆栈确实会随着中间值的增加而增大和缩小。
So when you call a function and you begin executing its body values will be popped
因此，当您调用一个函数并开始执行它的体值时，将弹出
and pushed onto the stack beside the activation record. So think back to the
并推送到激活记录旁边的堆栈上。所以回想一下
code generation for plus and minus and if then else intermediate values were being
加号和减号的代码生成，如果是，则中间值为
pushed and popped from the stack And so what this means is that these variables
从堆栈中推入和弹出，这意味着这些变量
that are in the activation record are not at a fixed offset From the stack pointer.
在激活记录中的值与堆栈指针的偏移不是固定的。
So we can't use the stack point very easily to the side or to find those
所以我们不能很容易地使用堆栈指针到一边或找到那些
variables. So the solution is to use the frame pointer. The frame pointer always
变量。因此，解决方案是使用帧指针。帧指针始终
points to the return address in the activation record and because it doesn't
指向激活记录中的返回地址，因为它没有
move during the execution of the function body, we can always find the variables at
MOVE在函数体的执行过程中，我们总是可以在以下位置找到变量
the same place relative to the frame pointer. So, how do we do that? Well,
相对于帧指针的相同位置。那么，我们该怎么做呢？井,
let's consider the i-th argument, X of I and does the i-th argument to
让我们考虑第i个参数，即i的X，并将第i个参数
the, to the function. So where is that going to be relative to the frame pointer?
这个，到这个函数。那么它相对于帧指针的位置是什么呢？
That will be at offset Z from the frame pointer And Z is just four times I. Right,
这将位于距帧指针的偏移量Z处，而Z仅是I的四倍。好的，
and this is actually the reason here for generating for pushing the arguments on
这实际上就是在这里生成推论的原因
the stack in reverse order, starting with the last argument to the function, because
堆栈的顺序相反，从函数的最后一个参数开始，因为
it just makes this index calculation simple. It wouldn't be that much more
它只是使这个指数的计算变得简单。不会再多了
complicated if we pushed the arguments in the other order. It just makes it a little
如果我们把论据推到另一个顺序，情况就复杂了。它只是让它变得有点
easier to see how the indexing works And anyway this index, this offset, is being
更容易看到索引是如何工作的，而且无论如何，这个索引、这个偏移量
calculated at compile time. So, notice that this number, this four times I, is
在编译时计算。所以，请注意这个数字，这四倍于I，是
something that the compiler knows, and what we're putting in the code here is
编译器知道的东西，我们在这里放入的代码是
just a fixed offset. So, we are not actually doing that multiplication at run
只是一个固定的偏移量。因此，我们实际上没有在运行时进行乘法运算
time. See here is just a number, as computed statically by the compiler. So
时间到了。这里只是一个数字，由编译器静态计算。所以
anyway We just load and off send Z which is the four times I where I is the index,
不管怎样，我们只需要加载和关闭Z，它是I的四倍，其中I是索引，
the position of the variable in the list of parameters. At that offset from the
变量在参数列表中的位置。在该偏移量处
frame pointer, that's where XI is stored in the activation record And we just load
帧指针，这是XI存储在激活记录中的位置，我们只需加载
it into the accumulator. So that is the entire code generation for a variable
把它放到蓄电池里。这就是变量的整个代码生成过程
reference. Here's a little example. So for the function, the hypothetical function
参考。这里有一个小例子。所以对于函数，假设函数
that we've been looking at, with two parameters x and y. X is going to be at
这是我们一直在看的，有两个参数x和y，x将在
the frame pointer +four and y will be at the frame pointer +eight.
帧指针+4和y将位于帧指针+8。